You know that projects are a temporary endeavor to create a unique product service condition or result
projects also have a characteristic and that is they drive change that projects are changing the current
state to a desired future state that projects are moving from where we are now to a desired state of
what our goals are where we want to be.
So projects are always doing really one of four activities when we're driving change.
We're moving something we're adding something or changing something or deleting something.
And yes you have to do those hand motions when you talk about moving adding changing deleting.
So they're not really going to have to do that.
And then I hope you remember those.
So you're moving adding changing deleting sometimes called Mac D.
All right now it's important to recognize this is a quick test.
Are you really doing a project.
Are you changing.
So projects are about change.
So you're moving from your current state to that desired future state.
Now it's possible often likely especially in I.T. that there's a transition state a transition period
as you're making this move.
So imagine that we are on you know Windows X whatever version is popular.
Now we're on Windows X and here comes a new version of Microsoft Windows Windows y which I've often
have asked that question.
All right.
So moving from X to Y we got thousands of people in our network that we support that we're going to
have to go from x to y.
So we can't flip the switch all at once.
What we do is kind of a rolling release by department by department so our transition state would be
some people are going to be on Windows y that we've made the transition for them.
But other people are still on Windows x.
So now we have dual support so that introduces some issues and some risk and maybe some you know some
resource constraints that we have to consider in our project this transition stage.
And then you know as more and more people come over to Windows Why is less and less of an issue and
a risk.
But we have to plan for this operational transfer a transition state can also be that I'm giving the
product to someone else the support of putting it into production doesn't have to be I-T could be a
new piece of equipment or a new solution or you know even a building.
So there some type of a warranty or a support period that as we're putting this new piece of equipment
into place we just don't plug it in and walk away that there's a transition where we support that and
maintain it.
And you know help people ramp up on that new solution we've created for them.
So that's also a transition state.
All right great job.
See you in the next lecture.